oecd.org 2019-12-03

# Privacy Policy - OECD

_Updated: 2 May 2019  
_

The OECD is committed to the protection of personal information of the users of its websites. OECD Staff and external processors who have access to personal information and are associated with the processing of that information are obligated to respect the privacy and confidentiality of information, consistent with the Decision of Secretary-General on the Protection of Individuals with Regard to the Processing of their Personal Data ([Annex XII of the Staff Manual](https://www.oecd.org/careers/Staff_Rules_EN.pdf#page=374)).

This Privacy Policy statement is based on the [Recommendation of the Council concerning Guidelines on the Protection of Privacy and Transborder Flows of Personal Data](https://legalinstruments.oecd.org/en/instruments/OECD-LEGAL-0188).

####   
**  
Information Collection**

If you visit OECD websites to read or download information, the OECD collects and stores only the following information that is automatically recognised: the date and time, the originating IP address, the domain name, the type of browser and operating system used (if provided by the browser), the URL of the referring page (if provided by the browser), the object requested and the completion status of the request.

More information is collected and logged for advanced features, such as placing an order on OECD web servers for online payments, downloading from the online library ([OECD iLibrary](http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/)), subscribing to an OECD newsletter (OECDdirect) or using the personalisation features (MyOECD).

#### **Use of Collected Informatio** n

Anonymous information is collected from visits to OECD websites to measure user activity on these websites. This includes analysing these logs periodically to measure the traffic through the servers, the number of pages visited and the level of demand for pages and topics of interest, and to help the OECD provide better customer service. The logs may be preserved indefinitely and used at any time and in any way to prevent security breaches and to ensure the integrity of the data on the servers. This information is collected through the use of various technologies, including "cookies".

Moreover, the following information is associated with the cookie: IP address, session number, customer ID (first name, last name and job function) and identification number for online payments, if used. If the user has chosen to "remember login and password", those two items are encrypted and also associated with the cookie. When a registered MyOECD user returns to the site without logging in, the ID stored in the cookie is used to track the user (unless the user manually deleted the cookie, at which point the server will automatically create another cookie). If you do not want your transaction details used in this manner, you can disable cookies in your browser.

Please note that the personal information recorded when you voluntarily registered for the "MyOECD" service, is extracted in an anonymous format and then analysed at an aggregate level to help the OECD understand trends and patterns. None of this information is reviewed at an individual level, nor associated with any other personal information.

#### **Your Choice**

Registration on OECD websites is optional. If you choose not to register or actively provide personal information, you can still use OECD websites. However, certain features that require registration may be unavailable (for example, online purchases or e-mail alerts).

OECD websites may enable you to communicate with other users and to post information accessible by others. You should be aware that when you choose to use these services, your information may be available to other users, and the OECD has no control over the use of your information by these users.

You may also choose to receive promotional or marketing information from other organisations. When you do so, the OECD will only disclose your name and physical and electronic addresses to them. However, you should note that these organisations may follow privacy policies and practices which may be different from those of the OECD. At any time you can ask the OECD not to further disclose your name and addresses by sending an e-mail to the relevant contacts indicated on the website where you registered, e.g. [oecddirect@oecd.org](mailto:oecddirect@oecd.org), [oecdilibrary@oecd.org](mailto:oecdilibrary@oecd.org) or [webmaster@oecd.org](mailto:webmaster@oecd.org).

With the "MyOECD" function, the OECD provides a personalised URL (link) that brings you to a personalised web page. By using this option, you agree to let OECD collect information about your session visits. This information helps the OECD provide you with information that matches your interests. Please note that if you register to “MyOECD”, your information may be made available to OECD staff and to Member countries delegations for the purpose of events management. 

#### **Links**

Throughout the OECD websites, you may find links to other third-party websites. Please note that the OECD is not responsible for the privacy policies or content on third-party websites.

OECD websites may also include links to third-party web servers for online payments, which may have different privacy policies. You are therefore encouraged to review their privacy policies, when visiting these websites.

#### **Individual Access and Right to Correction**

You can ask the OECD whether it is keeping personal information about you, and you can also request to receive a copy of that personal information. As a safeguard against abuse the OECD will ask you to provide proof of your identity before providing you with any personal information. If you are not able to do so, the OECD reserves the right to refuse to send you the personal information.

You may request at any time that the OECD corrects your personal information in its records. You may also request the deletion of such information, except when it has been collected for a specific purpose for which you have given your consent, for the performance of a contract to which you are a party, or in order to comply with a legal obligation. For such requests, please send an e-mail to the relevant contacts indicated on the website where you registered, e.g. [oecddirect@oecd.org](mailto:oecddirect@oecd.org), [oecdilibrary@oecd.org](mailto:oecdilibrary@oecd.org) or [webmaster@oecd.org](mailto:webmaster@oecd.org).

If you have further queries or complaints related to the processing of your personal data, please contact:

Data Protection Officer   
E-mail: [DPO@oecd.org](mailto:DPO@oecd.org)

For further assistance in resolving claims related to personal data protection please contact:

Data Protection Commissioner  
E-mail: [DPC@oecd.org](mailto:DPC@oecd.org)

#### **Notification of Changes**

As the OECD creates new services that may generate a need to amend this privacy policy statement, you will find here the previous privacy policy statement.

#### ** **
